Wie blickst du seit dem 7. Oktober auf Europa und den zunehmenden Antisemitismus?
We see what is going on around the world,
and it is scary. And today,
I trust the UAE and Bahrain.
Far more than I trust Spain
or Italy or France.
I think that Germany
has done a very smart move after the Holocaust:
Germany took responsibility and accountability.
And that's what you don’t see many,
many other people do.
Not just about the Holocaust in general.
You speak about the Turks,
what they're doing to the Kurds,
Everyone around the world
is having a hard time taking responsibility,
and accountability.
Germany did not.
Germany took accountability for what has happened
and made sure that it indoctrinated their children,
to understand,
history and what has happened.
I think that today,
Germany is seeing the fruit of that because
I think that Germany is far more,
cautious about going against
the Jews without having
reasons or things that they know for sure,
that are not stupid empty propaganda.
I think that the Germans, with their indoctrination
throughout the years after the Holocaust,
have done a lot in order to keep themselves,
to keep them their critical thinking alive.
And I think
that's a very big difference
between the countries.
It’s not stable, firstly,
we’re talking about politics,
and we’re talking about politicians.
Let's not forget that.
The second thing is that still,
if you compare it to what is happening in other countries,
you do have that,
but you also have a very strong other side,
you also have people that are strongly defending
the idea of
be cooperating with Israel and all that.
So I think that you still have that balance,
I don’t think that Germany needs to go after Israel
"whatever happens"
We’re talking about critical thinking,
I know what people see around the world today can make them...
I see the news,
what is reported, the news are very biased,
most of the channels are extremely biased.
So I think that it’s a political
and a media kind of thing.
Politicians are trying to get more support.
But still,
I wouldn’t even compare the situation in Germany,
or Austria for example,
to the situation in France and Italy
and Spain.
It’s way, way different.
it’s just now that I think about it,
but I think it all starts from accountability,
because again,
Australia is the one that also took accountability,
of the things
after the Holocaust.
I think it has a lot to do with that.
Every time that as a Jew, I travel around Europe,
every country I come to, they tell me:
"Oh we were not with the Nazis",
"but they, they were with the Nazis".
And as I walk through I go like
"What the fuck nobody was with the Nazis",
but somehow they became so big
but nobody went with them,
so I think that many countries just
don’t take accountability and
There are some countries that I will not go to,
because it just seems not safe.
In general
there are a lot of things going on today,
look at Paris, look at who wants to travel there?
you want to travel, you want to have fun,
you don’t want to get into this,
and many European countries are not fun to travel today.
That's one reason.
I will not stop myself from going somewhere
because a), terrorists don’t make my schedule,
and b),
I've lived here for 20 years.
I'm not scared of them. I survived a massacre.
I'm not scared of them.
They can all fuck off, I don’t give a fuck really.
Sorry for my language but seriously,
If I didn’t believe that I will die when I need to,
I wouldn’t be able to live here.
You need to have a certain
way of looking at life,
in order to not jump when this is heard.
You need to have a certain...
So, no it wouldn’t stop me.
I wouldn’t go because it doesn’t look fun,
but if I needed to go or wanted to go,
it wouldn’t stop me,
I believe.